FLORIAN BÜHLER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

I am a 29-year-old mathematician and full stack web developer with a strong handson mentality and over 4 years of experience in building web applications from front to back in agile teams. I possess a strong analytical, problem-solving and methodical mindset and I love to use new technologies to solve complex problems.

EXPERIENCE

d-fine, Germany - Senior Consultant / Web Developer

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

Feature Implementation for a Crypto Currency Custodian

- Streamlined the reporting process by implementing a new React frontend, enabling the business team to finish the reporting in less than half the time.
- Improved the backend functionality to increase the product range.
- Automated manual setup of local development environments with JavaScript.

Feature Implementation for a Microservice Tokenization Platform

- Restructured an existing React single page application to a modular structure in order to deliver features more rapidly.
- Created several larger React components for login, page navigation and display of user data in close consultation with the product owner.
- Built a multilingual and responsive landing page with Gatsby and React.
- Achieved higher consistency between multiple applications and reduced code duplication by the creation of a React component library.
- Designed and implemented new REST API endpoints for ASP.NET Core microservices to achieve product requirements.

d-fine, Germany - Consultant / Web Developer

MARCH 2017 - JUNE 2020

Development of a Mobile Coupon Platform

- Built a responsive landing page using Gatsby in cooperation with a UX designer.
- Built React components for multiple views, including the coupon overview, coupon details and for the ordering process.
- Trained new developer and supported him with daily pair programming sessions for the first few sprints.
- Created GitLab CI/CD pipelines to test, build and deploy the application to AWS.

Development of a Microservice Platform (MVP)

- Built multiple reusable components for a React SPA prototype to collect and display user data.
- Designed and implemented business logic from the REST API to the database layer in a microservices based backend.

EDUCATION

Ulm University, Germany – *M. Sc. in Mathematics and Economics* OCTOBER 2014 – NOVEMBER 2016

Middle East Technical University, Turkey – Erasmus Semester

OCTOBER 2015 - JANUARY 2016

Ulm University, Germany – *B. Sc. in Mathematics and Economics* OCTOBER 2011 – JULY 2014

CONTACT

- Amselweg 17 88489 Wain, Germany
- **** +49 174 5229510
- ✓ florian-buehler@outlook.com
- florianbuehler.github.io
- in linkedin.com/in/florian-bühler
- github.com/florianbuehler

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript / ES6

TypeScript

React.js

Redux

HTML5

CSS3 / Sass

Gatsby

C#

ASP.NET Core

Node.js

REST APIs

Postgres

Docker

Scrum

Git / GitHub / GitLab

CI/CD Pipelines

Domain-Driven Design

Test-Driven Design

LANGUAGES

German (native)

English (proficient)

Chinese (beginner)

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master

GitLab Certified Associate